<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Completed Project on Dr Jinbin Zhu</title>
    <link>/tags/completed-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Completed Project on Dr Jinbin Zhu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Jinbin Zhu 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/completed-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Operational Research Driven By Software Engineering Principles</title>
      <link>/project/2018-softorse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2018-softorse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; Since Operational Research (OR) discovered &amp;ldquo;wicked&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;messy&amp;rdquo; problems, many contributions have been made to simplify the solving of this type of situations. These methodologies are usually known as Soft-OR. However, there are still gaps in this research area. Software Engineering (SE) has addressed this gaps before and, due to the similarity that exists between both disciplines, this project aims to apply SE concepts, techniques and methods to OR interventions. The overall goal is to assist in the development of OR models and to provide means to enhance their code quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyphothesis:&lt;/strong&gt; Software Engineering concepts can contribute and assist in the development of Operational Research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participants:&lt;/strong&gt; Dr. Jinbin Zhu, Dr. Laura Cunico.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis, Characterization, Design and Development of APS to Optimize Manufacturing Processes</title>
      <link>/project/2013-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2013-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; This project aims to study Advanced Planning Systems (APS) from a Software Engineering (SE) point of view, aiming to bridge the current gap in research, providing sound concepts and definitions founded in current international SE standars. It aims to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provide a definition that would consider APS as systems and not only as models, including generic Functional Requirements and Quality Attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Propose means to improve exchange of manufacturing information with Enterprise Systems by using the standardized concepts of the ANSI/ISA-95 standard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generate and evaluate a Reference Architecture to characterize the APS domain and simplify future in-house development of APS modules in SME (Small and Medium Enterprises).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was my PhD thesis. Degree: PhD on Information Systems Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participants:&lt;/strong&gt; Eng. Jinbin Zhu, Prof. Jorge Marcelo Montagna (Co-Advisor), Prof. Aldo Vecchietti (Advisor).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information System to Solve Industrial Planning and Scheduling Problems</title>
      <link>/project/2012-pfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2012-pfc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goal:&lt;/strong&gt; The project objective was to develop software system prototype that would act as a framework to easily integrate planning and scheduling mathematical optimization models for manufacturing processes, to an organization Enterprise System. Key qualities of the prototype were: the ability to change models easily without requiring reprogramming, and a simple and configurable set up of the Enterprise System to interoperate with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was the Thesis from my Information Systems Engineering degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participants:&lt;/strong&gt; Jinbin Zhu, Dr. Maria Analia Rodriguez (Co-Advisor), Prof. Aldo Vecchietti (Advisor).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
